[Music]
i visited the plant nursery today one of
my favorite places in my town
i was looking for a new virginia creeper
to plant by the trellis of my cottage
while i was there i noticed one of the
very large trees had recently had some
branches cut back
the flowers around it looked a bit
ragged and a very kind gardener
explained that they were having a
hard time adjusting to being exposed to
the sun now that the shade was gone
she assured me that while the plants
were struggling at the moment over time
their roots would reach deeper and their
bodies strengthen
and they would learn to thrive in their
new environment even if it wasn't what
they may have preferred
nature's resilience and willingness to
thrive wherever it is
will never cease to inspire me
the gardener as well told me that no
matter how the plants
struggled she was a committed steward of
the land and would keep an eye on them
if ever they needed some extra help her
words got me thinking about the beauty
of a committed relationship
in this case of a human and a garden and
how there was a time in my life when i
feared obligations like that
my life has changed a lot
[Music]
as a teen i saw a nine to five and
relational commitments
as things that impacted my freedom and
ability to pursue my actual dreams
and in movies and books and online i see
that this is a common belief in my
society
we celebrate people who break free of
the mold and do things differently
often going on a very individual
adventure usually free of multiple
commitments and sometimes even their own
family
they often discover a lot about
themselves and who they are in the
process
i notice many characters in movies
randomly pack their bags
empty their bank accounts and go off to
see the world
of course there's nothing wrong with
this i just don't think it's feasible
for most of us at least not me
and before i go further remember that i
can only speak from the perspective of
my own story
it isn't a universal truth and of course
i would love to hear your insights
[Music]
personally i think we do not always
highlight enough the beauty of a life
lived in one place with strong bonds
obligations and commitments
our lives lived for others as much as
for ourselves
even if to the detriment of our own
personal dreams
my mother came from a very poor family
who worked tirelessly to get her the
opportunity to go to the us
learn english and be a first generation
student
she dedicated her life to helping her
own family live comfortably and provide
for myself and my siblings
but she and my father worked hard to
give us stability and support
i have no doubt they have given up
certain dreams for us
accepting that their children would
impact their entire lives
i really want to celebrate the
incredible lifelong sacrifices
so many people make for others i think
it's beautiful
sometimes our dreams need to change
depending on circumstance and that's
okay
new dreams can be just as rewarding if i
have a child my dreams will change
when my parents are older if my rabbit
escapes and eats my entire garden
i will have to rethink my plan too
my dreams are important and i pursue
them in practical ways but
it's just not possible sometimes and
then i restructure that dream or commit
myself to living a new one
i wish we celebrated more of the people
who work jobs they don't necessarily
love
or not living in their ideal place but
it doesn't matter
because they love their families and
friends and will do what is needed to
take care of them
[Music]
i transitioned to a new job and moved to
this place not because i necessarily
wanted to
it was because it was the only place i
could get the temporary help i needed
from my parents
i was actually giving up much of what i
thought of as freedom by coming here
but in time i grew to see the idea of
living freely in more relative terms
as a teacher i felt a great obligation
to my job i have a relationship that
takes time and commitment to maintain
and it is an enormous obligation in and
of itself
my abuela lived with us for many years
when i was a child
as it is typical in hispanic culture to
have many generations under one roof
through that experience i became
dedicated to the idea of one day
providing for my
own parents as a caregiver in any way i
was able
this was another obligation that i have
welcomed into my life
further cementing me here and committing
myself to live in one place for the long
term
[Music]
i have found lasting satisfaction in
forming bonds with the place and its
people while it makes it harder to leave
there's something very special about
living this way as well
it's how most of us live our lives
greatly impacted by responsibility of
family
or children or a job and i think that's
why we elevate the stories of people who
live differently
who have unusual jobs or live in an
unusual way
and i'm most certainly not saying that
these people are wrong in any way to
live differently
i support them completely if that's what
brings them joy
i just wanted to take a moment and
celebrate the people who don't have
those opportunities
or have put their own wishes on hold for
others
of course i know the weight of
expectation put on you by other people
and know that that is not always a
positive burden to bear and that there
is definitely a time and place to walk
away from commitments
when they are detrimental and that is a
very brave thing to do
[Music]
my boyfriend was born and raised here
and he takes such great pride in being
able to know all the mountain peaks by
name
and notice changes over time he has an
extremely detailed knowledge of the area
that few people can boast he's a
surveyor and spends many days each year
traversing the mountain slopes on the
hunt for clear and smoky quartz crystals
i'm amazed by his vast understanding of
this valley that he could have only
gotten from living here for many many
years
and it inspired me to spread my roots
and dedicate myself to life of learning
to understand my home
as you can see one way i've done that is
through learning the art of growing new
life in the garden
if you notice there's a lot of weeds
it's because there is
but i do my best the time i have
and that's all we really need to do
anyway i hope you have a wonderful day
or night
sending you my love
[Music]
do
you